## **Andrew Bridger**

(m) +44 7759 512091

(e) andrewjohnbridger@gmail.com (w) https://andybridger.github.io/

### **Professional Overview**

I am an Economist who is passionate about applying and communicating economic principles to create better outcomes for all. I have 5 years professional experience in economic policy and research. I am on a sabbatical from the Australian Industry Group, where I hold a Senior Economist role, to complete my Master of Science in Economics at the University of Edinburgh, Scotland.

## **Professional Experience**

## Senior Economist The Australian Industry Group (Ai Group)

Dec 2017 – Current Melbourne and Brisbane, Australia

Responsible for analysis and commentary on Australian and international economic developments. I started as an Economist in 2017 and was promoted to Senior Economist in 2019.

### Key responsibilities:

- Providing economic advice and research
- Constructing data visualisations
- Presenting economic updates to Government agencies, journalists and business
- Statistical and policy analysis
- Preparing Ai Group business surveys and research reports
- Supervising and supporting junior colleagues

# Data Analyst Department of Industry, Innovation and Science

Feb 2016 – Dec 2017 Canberra, Australia

Worked across industry growth sectors, modelling workforce requirements to deliver government services and the budget process, including costing new policy proposals.

## Key responsibilities:

- Modelling workforce requirements and making recommendations based on the modelling to the Executive
- Budget analysis including costing new policy proposals
- Reporting on recent foreign investment trends in the Australian economy

# Research Economist Synergies Economic Consulting

Jan 2015 – Jul 2015 Brisbane, Australia

Hired as a summer intern and upon completion of my internship, I was asked to stay on while finishing my university studies.

### Key responsibilities:

- Economic research on wheat supply chains, port facilities and the energy market
- Policy updates
- Report writing

## **Early Career Summary**

lpsos Research 2013 - 2015

Computer Assisted Telephone Interviewer

Strut N Fret Festival Bar Team 2012 - 2014

Bartender

### Qualifications

Master of Science in Economics University of Edinburgh

2021 - Current Edinburgh, UK

- Course component completed in May 2022
- Dissertation to be completed by August 2022

## Bachelor of Commerce/Economics University of Queensland

2011-2015 Brisbane, Australia

- Majored in Finance (Commerce) and Quantitative Methods (Economics)
- Grade Point Average of 5.6 (out of 7)
- Exchange semesters at the University of Massachusetts and Kansas State University
- 2012 Dean's Commendation for High Achievement

## Graduate Certificate in Management (Public Sector) University of Canberra

2017

Canberra, Australia

• Grade Point Average of 6.0 (out of 7)

## **Summary of Skills**

- Data analysis to inform decision-making
- Excellent written communication skills
- Statistical software (R and STATA)
- Advanced excel skills

- Ability to present complex economic concepts to a lay audience
- Enthusiasm for responsibility
- Attention to detail

### Referees

Contact details available upon request

## Julie Toth

Principal at Nous Group Australia Former Chief Economist at The Australian Industry Group

#### Lisa Hind

General Manager of Strategy and Operations at the Australian National Measurement Institute Former General Manager of the State and Territory Network at the Australian Department of Industry, Innovation and Science

#### Jeffrey Lassen

Managing Director at FTI Consulting Former Principal at Synergies Economic Consulting